A Finding Aid to the Lois Dodd Papers, 1945-2013, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Addition to the Lois Dodd Papers, 1945-2013; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 4.8 Linear feet Box 3-8
  - Project and Teaching Files, 1965-2002; 8.4; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 6
    - Exhibitions, Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
      - 304 High Street, Jean Cohen, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - 304 High Street, William White and Artists for Environment, circa 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Delaware Water Gap Project, Artists for Environment, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - "Six Figurative Sculptors," Curated by Dodd at Maine Coast Artists Gallery, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - National Academy of Design, 1993-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8-10)
    - Teaching Files, Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
      - Brooklyn College, 1965-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11-13)
      - Brooklyn College MFA Program, Deputy Chair, 1990-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Queens College, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Personal Business Records, 1966-2000s; 8.5; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Box 6
    Personal business records date from 1966-2000s and are sales receipts, price lists, and correspondence with several galleries that represented Dodd over the years. Some printed material and photographic prints of artwork are found here as well.
    - Cape Split Place Inc., 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Fischbach Gallery, 1980s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
    - Green Mountain Gallery, 1969-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Mobile Art Gallery Ltd. and Two Gallery, 1976; 1966-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Printed Material, 1945-2013; 8.6; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Box 6
    Printed material dates from 1945-2012 and documents Dodd's life and career and the careers of her friends. Found here are announcements, brochures, clippings, exhibition catalogs, newsletters, periodicals, and various other printed material. The issue of ARTnews features an interview with Dodd. The other periodical is an issue of the magazine of Museum: A Project of Living Artists. A few files of printed material are arranged by subject, primarily by artist name.
    - Announcements, 1952-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Brochures, 1945-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Clipping, John Canaday, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1960-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Newsletters, 1977-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Periodicals, 1975; 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Various Printed Material, 1967-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - By Subject, Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
      - Artists for Environment Foundation, 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Charles Cajori, 1960s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Jean Cohen, 1977-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Lucien Day, 1980s-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - Tanager Gallery, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Tom Wesselmann, 1987-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Photographic Material, 1950s-2000s; 8.7; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 7
    Photographic material dates from 1950s-2000s and is of artwork, Dodd, friends, family, and a few exhibition views. Dodd's artwork is captured on slides. All other material is black and white and color photographic prints. Found here are many shots of Dodd throughout her life, many of her painting in her studio.
    - Artwork, 1950s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Lois Dodd, Friends, and Family, 1950s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Exhibition Installation, 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Sketchbooks, 1986-1998; 8.8; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 7-8
    Eleven sketchbooks date from 1986-1998 and were used by Dodd on various trip to sketch landscapes and architecture. Media used include pencil, pen, and watercolor. Many sketches are labeled with the date and name of site.
    - Sketchbook, "Trip to Arizona and New Mexico", 1986 April; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Sketchbook, "Hanover, NH, and Vermont", 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Sketchbook, "Delaware Water Gap, Vermont Studio Center", 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Sketchbook, "Water Gap and Maine Night Walks", 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sketchbook, "Trip to Texas with Anne Arnold and Bob Brooks", 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Sketchbook, "New Orleans and Texas with Bob and Anne", 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Sketchbook, "Maine", 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Sketchbook, "Trip to Ucross with Elizabeth", 1994 March; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Sketchbook, "Maine, Vermont, 1995; Trip West, 1996", 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Sketchbook, "Turkey, 1995; Louisiana, 1998", Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Sketchbook, "Harrisville, New Hampshire; Owls Head, Maine", 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Artwork by Other Artist, 1981-1984; 8.9; Archival Resource Key; 1 Folder Box 8
    The artworks in this series are four prints by the artist George Schneeman, which were incorporated into a calendar for the years 1981-1984.
    - Calendar Prints, George Schneeman, 1981-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 8)